Guide to the Administrative Papers of President John Crittenden Sawhill 1974-1981 (Bulk 1975-1979) RG.3.0.8
New York University Archives
- Series X: Schools and Divisions
  Gallatin Division material (which incorporates the previously-known-as University Without Walls unit, (UWW)) is limited. There the issue of the moment concerned the proposed transformation from the UWW, a unit "that integrates work, internships and independent study," NYU News Bureau release 2/8/72, Box 69, folder 8, into a permanent, successor unit to be known as the Gallatin Division. This proposal was presented by the President in conjunction with his plan for the reorganization of SCE, Box 67, folder 3 above. Sawhill addressed the members of the University Senate 1/22/76 on these plans, following up on this with a position paper to the University community, 3/4/76, also Box 69, folder 8.
  School of Law documentation appearing in Box 69, folders 11-15 is routine. The primary matter at the institutional level concerned the disposition of the school-owned C.F. Mueller Spaghetti Company; these records are in Box 70, folders 1-5. Information on the sale of the company to Foremost-McKesson, Inc. and the division of the proceeds between the University endowment and the School of Law is found in Sawhill to NYU Trustees 9/28/76, folder 3; for establishment of the $67.5 million school endowment and a school long range planning committee, see Dean Norman Redlich to Sawhill and Trustees of the Law Center Foundation, 11/23/76, folder 9.
  Medical Center and Schools of Medicine materials follow. While substantial in amount, Box 70, folders 12-16 and Box 71, folders 1-15, the content, like that of the School of Law, is generally routine. There is, however, a Medical Center Fact Sheet 4/80 in Box 70, folder 16 and a Case Study Grant Management document (late 1975?) Box 70, folder 12, which offer considerable detail on the history, structure and general administrative functioning of the Medical Center, while Box 71, folders 10-14 provides a multi-year budget survey.
  Graduate School of Public Administration (GPA) records occupy the first 5 folders in Box 72. Two of them, folders 1-2, offer general information. Of the three remaining files, one is titled Advisory Council, one Decanal Memoranda, and the third, Center for Science and Technology Policy. Tensions between students in GPA's Health program and the school can be picked up in folder 1, along with a newly developed "GPA Governance Charter," adopted by the GPA Faculty-Student Council 10/19/76, and a sampling of Dean Dick Netzer's memoranda on a variety of administrative matters. Folder 2 contains further material on issues at the school and decanal level, including additional Netzer memos.
  School of Social Work (SSW) material is modest in quantity and, in general, routine in scope, with a decanal resignation, search and appointment process fitting into its on-going rhythm, Box 72, folders 6-10. SSW had recently emerged from a period of great turmoil, during which its continued existence was in doubt, and the material here reflects its success in returning to normal operations. See Borowitz Papers, Box 73, folders 8-18 and Box 74, folder 1 for this history.
  The contents of the final 8 folders in Box 72 comprise the School of the Arts record. The activities of the school's Advisory Council are well-documented, in folders 16-18. The balance of these materials is routine.
  The next section of Series X is taken up with the two non-FAS divisions with records in this collection, the Institute of Afro-American Affairs and the New York Institute for the Humanities (NYIH). They occupy Box 73, Afro-American Affairs in folders 1-2, and the NYIH the balance. One important event in the limited Afro-American Affairs collection was the resignation of the Institute's founding director, Roscoe Brown, and the undertaking of a search for a successor, folders 1-2. Documentation of the conceptualization and planning for what became the NYIH, including a background paper by Sawhill, titled "The State of Higher Education in the City," and presented by him at a conference on the future of the Intellectual Community in New York City 12/10-11/76 at NYU, a draft prospectus, 7/77, and several discussion drafts, 8/77, 9/21 and 10/77 constitute the NYIH material and offer insight into the thinking and the process by which it came into being, folders 3-11.
  The final section of Series X has been subdivided in three. Subseries I, titled "Interschool," contains the record of the Interschool Committee on Undergraduate Education, 10/77-3/79, Box 74, folders 1-2. Subseries II is titled "Transition to Bennett Acting Presidency, ACADEMIC." Folders 3-5 contain Bennett-annotated Academic Long Range Planning materials; beginning with folder 6, and continuing through Box 75, folder 12, are Bennett-annotated school and division Annual Reports for 1978-1979. Subseries III occupies the majority of Box 76, and is titled "Transition to Bennett Acting Presidency, ADMINISTRATIVE-FINANCIAL." Folders 1-2 contain Bennett-annotated briefing materials, while the content of the remainder of this series, folders 3-8, covers computer facilities, cost allocation reports for 1978-1979 and 1979-1980, financial affairs and long-range compensation.
  - Arts and Science (FAS), Jul 1975-Dec 1976 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Arts and Science (FAS), Jan 1977-Jul 1977 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Arts and Science (FAS), Sep 1977-Jul 1978 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Arts and Science (FAS), Nov 1978-Jan 1979 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Arts and Science (FAS), Feb 1979-Apr 1979 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Arts and Science (FAS), May 1979-Jul 1979 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Arts and Science (FAS), Sep 1979-Jun 1980 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Arts and Science (FAS); Budget & Financial Matters, Jul 1975-Mar 1980 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Arts and Science (FAS); Dean, Aug 1975-Oct 1978 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Arts and Science (FAS); Development Plan, Jan 1980-Feb 1980 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Arts and Science (FAS); Faculty Meeting Minutes, Sep 1975-Feb 1980 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Arts and Science (FAS); Institute for Public and Foreign Affairs, Nov 1976-Mar 1977 (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - Arts and Science (FAS); Institute for Hebrew and Judaic Studies, Dec 1976-Aug 1978 (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - Arts and Science (FAS); Search for Dean, Feb 1976-May 1978 (Box 62, Folder 14)
  - Arts and Science (FAS) (GSAS), Mar 1974-Jun 1976 (Box 62, Folder 15)
  - Arts and Science (FAS) (GSAS), Oct 1976-Jul 1977 (Box 62, Folder 16)
  - Arts and Science (FAS) (GSAS), Oct 1977-Sep 1980 (Box 62, Folder 17)
  - Arts and Science (GSAS); Admissions, Feb 1976-Feb 1979 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Arts and Science (GSAS); Doctoral Program Evaluation, Oct 1975-Jan 1980 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Arts and Science (WSUC), Sep 1975-May 1977 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Arts and Science (WSUC), Dec 1977-Apr 1980 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Divisions (FAS); Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, Oct 1975-Aug 1976 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Divisions (FAS); Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, Sep 1976-Aug 1978 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Divisions (FAS); Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, Dec 1978-Aug 1979 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Divisions (FAS); Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences, Sep 1979-May 1980 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Divisions (FAS); Institute of Fine Arts, Apr 1975-Jul 1976 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Divisions (FAS); Institute of Fine Arts, Sep 1976-Jul 1977 (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Divisions (FAS); Institute of Fine Arts, Oct 1977-Aug 1978 (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Divisions (FAS); Institute of Fine Arts, Sep 1978-Apr 1980 (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - Divisions (FAS); Institute of Fine Arts; Board of Trustees, Apr 1976-Apr 1980 (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - Divisions (FAS); Institute of Fine Arts; J. M. Hester File, Dec 1971-Feb 1973 (Box 63, Folder 14)
  - Divisions (FAS); Institute of Fine Arts; Search for Director, Jan 1978-Mar 1979 (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - Divisions (FAS); Institute of French Studies, Nov 1978-Jun 1979 (Box 63, Folder 16)
  - Divisions (FAS); Goethe Institute (Deutsches Haus), Oct 1976-Nov 1977 (Box 63, Folder 17)
  - Divisions (FAS); Goethe Institute (Deutsches Haus), Mar 1978-Dec 1979 (Box 63, Folder 18)
  - Divisions (FAS); Le Maison Francaise, Mar 1976-Dec 1979 (Box 63, Folder 19)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), Anthropology, Sep 1976-Jul 1980 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), Applied Science, Oct 1974-Aug 1978 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), Applied Science, Sep 1978-Jan 1980 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), Biology, Aug 1976-Dec 1977 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), Biology, Jan 1978-Jul 1980 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), Biology; Chairmanship, Jan 1978-Sep 1980 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), Biology; Development Plan, Aug 1978-Jan 1980 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), Chemistry-Computer Science, Dec 1975-May 1980 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), Economics, Dec 1975-Jul 1980 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), English, Nov 1975-Feb 1978 (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), English, Mar 1978-Dec 1979 (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), Fine Arts, French and Italian, Jun 1975-Apr 1980 (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), German, Nov 1975-Feb 1976 (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), History-Linguistics, Sep 1975-Apr 1980 (Box 64, Folder 14)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), Music, Near Eastern, Oct 1975-Jul 1980 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), Philosophy, Physics, Oct 1975-Jun 1979 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), Politics, May 1975-May 1979 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), Psychology, Oct 1975-May 1979 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), Slavic, Sociology, Nov 1975-Apr 1979 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Divisions, Departments (FAS), Spanish, Sep 1975-Sep 1980 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Business Schools (BPA), Sep 1975-Jul 1976 (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Business Schools (BPA), Sep 1976-Aug 1977 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Business Schools (BPA), Oct 1977-May 1980 (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Business Schools (BPA); Institute of Retail Management, Dec 1977-Jan 1980 (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Business Schools (GBA), Jul 1975-Dec 1975 (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - Business Schools (GBA), Feb 1976-Aug 1976 (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Business Schools (GBA), Sep 1976-Dec 1976 (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - Business Schools (GBA), Mar 1977-Aug 1977 (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - Business Schools (GBA), Sep 1977-Feb 1978 (Box 65, Folder 15)
  - Business Schools (GBA), Mar 1978-Aug 1978 (Box 65, Folder 16)
  - Business Schools (GBA), Sep 1978-Feb 1979 (Box 65, Folder 17)
  - Business Schools (GBA), Mar 1979-May 1979 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Business Schools (GBA), Jun 1979-Aug 1979 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Business Schools (GBA), Sep 1979-Oct 1980 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Business Schools (GBA), Accreditation Review, Apr 1979-May 1979 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Business Schools (GBA), Budget & Financial Matters, Jun 1975-Jun 1980 (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Business Schools (GBA), Search for Dean, Apr 1979-Apr 1980 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Continuing Education, School of, Jun 1975-Dec 1975 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Continuing Education, School of, Jan 1976-May 1976 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Continuing Education, School of, Jun 1976-Aug 1976 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Continuing Education, School of, Sep 1976-Jan 1977 (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Continuing Education, School of, Feb 1977-Aug 1977 (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - Continuing Education, School of, Sep 1977-Jan 1978 (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Continuing Education, School of, Feb 1978-Aug 1978 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Continuing Education, School of, Sep 1978-Mar 1980 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Continuing Education, School of; Sawhill Reorganization Proposal, Nov 1975-Jan 1976 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Continuing Education, School of; Sawhill Reorganization Proposal; Correspondence, Nov 1975 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Continuing Education, School of; Sawhill Reorganization Proposal; Correspondence, Dec 1975 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Continuing Education, School of; Sawhill Reorganization Proposal; Correspondence, Dec 1975 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Continuing Education, School of; Sawhill Reorganization Proposal; Correspondence, Dec 1975 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Continuing Education, School of; Sawhill Reorganization Proposal; Correspondence, Dec 1975 (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Continuing Education, School of; Sawhill Reorganization Proposal; Correspondence, Dec 1975 (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Continuing Education, School of; Sawhill Reorganization Proposal; Correspondence, Jan 1976-May 1977 (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - Continuing Education, School of; Sawhill Reorganization Proposal; Search for Dean, Feb 1976-Sep 1976 (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - Continuing Education, School of; Sawhill Reorganization Proposal; Sun Valley/NYU SCE Summer Seminar, Dec 1975-Sep 1977 (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - Continuing Education, School of; Sawhill Reorganization Proposal; WATCH Program, Jan 1979-Jun 1980 (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - Dentistry, College of, Sep 1975-Aug 1976 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Dentistry, College of, Sep 1976-Aug 1977 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Dentistry, College of, Sep 1977-Aug 1978 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Dentistry, College of, Sep 1978-Aug 1980 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Dentistry, College of; Accreditation Reviews, Jan 1977-Dec 1979 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Dentistry, College of; New York State and Dental Education, Jun 1975-May 1978 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Dentistry, College of; New York State and Dental Education, Sep 1978-Aug 1980 (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Dentistry, College of; Search for Dean, Mar 1978-May 1978 (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Education, School of, Aug 1975-Jan 1976 (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Education, School of, Feb 1976-Aug 1976 (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - Education, School of, Sep 1976-Feb 1977 (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Education, School of, Mar 1977-Aug 1977 (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - Education, School of, Sep 1977-Dec 1977 (Box 68, Folder 13)
  - Education, School of, Jan 1978-Aug 1978 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Education, School of, Sep 1978-Dec 1978 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Education, School of, Jan 1979-Aug 1979 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Education, School of, Sep 1979-Jan 1981 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Education, School of; Early Childhood Resource Center, Dec 1975-Sep 1976 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Education, School of; Faculty Meeting Minutes, Agenda, Nov 1975-May 1980 (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Education, School of; Faculty-Ed Council Meeting Minutes, Dec 1975-Oct 1976 (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - Gallatin Division (University Without Walls), Jun 1972-Jul 1976 (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Gallatin Division (University Without Walls), Sep 1976-Jul 1977 (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - Gallatin Division (University Without Walls), Sep 1977-Sep 1979 (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - Law, School of, Apr 1975-Jul 1976 (Box 69, Folder 11)
  - Law, School of, Sep 1976-Aug 1977 (Box 69, Folder 12)
  - Law, School of, Sep 1977-Feb 1978 (Box 69, Folder 13)
  - Law, School of, Mar 1978-Jun 1978 (Box 69, Folder 14)
  - Law, School of, Dec 1978-Jul 1980 (Box 69, Folder 15)
  - Law, School of; C. F. Mueller Company, Jan 1976-Jun 1976 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Law, School of; C. F. Mueller Company, Jul 1976-Aug 1976 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Law, School of; C. F. Mueller Company, Sep 1976-Oct 1976 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Law, School of; C. F. Mueller Company, Nov 1976-Nov 1977 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Law, School of; C. F. Mueller Company, Dec 1977-Jul 1980 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Law, School of; Faculty Meeting Minutes, May 1976-Mar 1978 (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Law, School of; Law Center Foundation, Aug 1974-Nov 1975 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Law, School of; Law Center Foundation, Dec 1975-Aug 1976 (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - Law, School of; Law Center Foundation, Nov 1976-Aug 1978 (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - Law, School of; Law Center Foundation, Nov 1978-Apr 1980 (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - Law, School of; Search Committee, Sep 1974 (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - Medical Center, Aug 1975-Aug 1976 (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - Medical Center, Sep 1976-Aug 1977 (Box 70, Folder 13)
  - Medical Center, Sep 1977-Jul 1978 (Box 70, Folder 14)
  - Medical Center, Sep 1978-Aug 1979 (Box 70, Folder 15)
  - Medical Center, Sep 1979-Sep 1980 (Box 70, Folder 16)
  - Medical Center; Board of Trustees, Jun 1975-Sep 1980 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Medical Center; Board of Trustees; Hospital and Institute Committee, Oct 1979-Feb 1980 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Medical Center; Data Systems Committee (Hospital Information System), Jun 1976-Feb 1980 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Medical Center; Environmental Medicine, Institute of, Jul 1977-Jan 1980 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Medical Center; Midtown Hospital, May 1975-Feb 1978 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Medical Center; Rehabilitation Medicine, Institute of, Jan 1976-Jun 1980 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Medicine, Schools of, Dec 1975-Dec 1976 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Medicine, Schools of, Feb 1977-Jun 1978 (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Medicine, Schools of, Oct 1978-Mar 1980 (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - Medicine, Schools of; Budget & Financial Matters, May 1975-Dec 1975 (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - Medicine, Schools of; Budget & Financial Matters, Jan 1976-May 1976 (Box 71, Folder 11)
  - Medicine, Schools of; Budget & Financial Matters, Sep 1976-Aug 1977 (Box 71, Folder 12)
  - Medicine, Schools of; Budget & Financial Matters, Sep 1977-Dec 1978 (Box 71, Folder 13)
  - Medicine, Schools of; Budget & Financial Matters, Jan 1979-Apr 1980 (Box 71, Folder 14)
  - Medicine, Schools of; Meeting Minutes, Sep 1975-Mar 1976 (Box 71, Folder 15)
  - Public Administration, Graduate School of, Nov 1975-Aug 1977 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Public Administration, Graduate School of, Sep 1977-Jul 1980 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - Public Administration, Graduate School of; Advisory Council, May 1976-Dec 1976 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Public Administration, Graduate School of; Decanal Memoranda, Nov 1976-Dec 1979 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Public Administration, Graduate School of; Science and Technology Policy, Center for, Jul 1978-Oct 1979 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Social Work, School of, Oct 1975-Sep 1979 (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Social Work, School of; Accreditation, Sep 1975-Mar 1976 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Social Work, School of; Advisory Council, Sep 1977-Jan 1978 (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Social Work, School of; Faculty Meeting Minutes, Dec 1975-Nov 1976 (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - Social Work, School of; Search for Dean, Apr 1977-Sep 1977 (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - Arts, School of the, Sep 1975-Apr 1976 (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - Arts, School of the, Oct 1976-Jul 1977 (Box 72, Folder 12)
  - Arts, School of the, Oct 1977-Jul 1978 (Box 72, Folder 13)
  - Arts, School of the, Sep 1978-Jul 1979 (Box 72, Folder 14)
  - Arts, School of the, Sep 1979-May 1980 (Box 72, Folder 15)
  - Arts, School of the; Advisory Council, Apr 1976 (Box 72, Folder 16)
  - Arts, School of the; Advisory Council, Apr 1977 (Box 72, Folder 17)
  - Arts, School of the; Advisory Council, Feb 1978-Feb 1980 (Box 72, Folder 18)
  - Divisions; Afro-American Affairs, Institute of, Jun 1975-May 1980 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Divisions; Afro-American Affairs, Institute of; Searches for Director, Nov 1977-Apr 1979 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - New York Institute for the Humanities, Apr 1976-Dec 1976 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - New York Institute for the Humanities, Jan 1977-Sep 1977 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - New York Institute for the Humanities, Oct 1977-Dec 1977 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - New York Institute for the Humanities, Jan 1978-May 1978 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - New York Institute for the Humanities, Jun 1978-Aug 1978 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - New York Institute for the Humanities, Sep 1978-Dec 1978 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - New York Institute for the Humanities, Jan 1979-Nov 1980 (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - New York Institute for the Humanities; Prospectus (Draft), Jul 1977 (Box 73, Folder 10)
  - New York Institute for the Humanities; Discussion Drafts, Sep 1977-Oct 1977 (Box 73, Folder 11)
  - Interschool Committee on Undergraduate Education; Academic Long Range Plan; FAS, CAS Annual Report; BPA Annual Report, 1977-1979 (Box 74)
  - GBA Annual Report, NY Institute for the Humanities Annual Report, 1978-1979 (Box 75)
- Series XI: Student Affairs
  This series is concerned with student matters. It fills one Hollinger box and portions of the preceding and succeeding ones, for a total of 1.75 linear feet. Folders 9-10 in Box 76, which open Series XI, contain primarily administrative and general materials, among them a copy of the University Senate-approved Student Disciplinary Procedures, 2/9/78, folder 9, and an emphasis on student retention and attrition concerns, 12/12/77, etc., folder 10. A report Preface and Summary, "The Quality of Undergraduate Life at New York University," Caroline Hodges Persell, 12/77 and some Admissions discussion and data complete the contents of Box 76. Routine student affairs documentation occupies Box 77, further admissions materials including reports and statistics, and tuition, folder 1-5, as well as 6 folders of information on student clubs and associations. The last section of this series occupies folders 1-17 in Box 78, where concluding topics range from more clubs material through financial aid, placement, publications, registrar, religious activities, ROTC, the student center (LOEB), and student conduct. The ROTC file, folder 15, contains some of the history relating to NYU's withdrawal from ROTC during the Vietnam War, the University's subsequent placement on a Department of Defense "blacklist" denying financial assistance to students wishing to study at NYU or other affected institutions, and the subsequent lifting of the blacklist.
  - Student Affairs, Sep 1975-Dec 1977 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Student Affairs, Jan 1978-Aug 1980 (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - Student Affairs; "The Quality of Undergraduate Life at New York University"; Report Preface and Summary of Results, Caroline Hodges Persell, Dec 1977 (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - Admissions, Aug 1975-May 1976 (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - Admissions, Oct 1976-Sep 1979 (Box 76, Folder 13)
  - Admissions; Recruiting, Oct 1975-Sep 1976 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Admissions; Recruiting, Mar 1977-May 1978 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Admissions; Reports and Statistics, Sep 1975-Dec 1978 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Admissions; Reports and Statistics, Feb 1979-Jul 1980 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Admissions; Tuition, Dec 1975-May 1979 (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Athletics, Jul 1975-Nov 1979 (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Clubs/Associations, Sep 1975-Feb 1976 (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Clubs/Associations, Mar 1976-Jul 1977 (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Clubs/Associations, Oct 1977-Jun 1980 (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - Clubs/Associations; Coalition of Private University Students, Jun 1975-Aug 1975 (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - Clubs/Associations; Committee on Student Life, Aug 1975-Dec 1978 (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - Clubs/Associations; Fraternities, Sep 1975-Jan 1980 (Box 77, Folder 12)
  - Clubs/Associations; Radio and Television, Aug 1975-May 1978 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Clubs/Associations; Student Councils, Jan 1976-Apr 1977 (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Dormitories, Aug 1975-May 1980 (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Financial Aid, Sep 1975-Nov 1976 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Financial Aid, Jan 1977-May 1978 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Financial Aid, Jul 1978-Nov 1980 (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Financial Aid; Scholarships and Grants, Sep 1975-Aug 1978 (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Financial Aid; Scholarships and Grants, Sep 1978-Sep 1980 (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - Placement Services, Sep 1975-Oct 1976 (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - Publications, Apr 1976-Sep 1977 (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - Publications; Newspapers, Sep 1975-Nov 1979 (Box 78, Folder 11)
  - Publications; Yearbooks, Dec 1975-Jun 1980 (Box 78, Folder 12)
  - Registrar, Sep 1975-Dec 1977 (Box 78, Folder 13)
  - Religious Activities, Nov 1975-Mar 1976 (Box 78, Folder 14)
  - ROTC, Jan 1975-Nov 1975 (Box 78, Folder 15)